savesmart.com 2010-12-12

# InfoSpace: Privacy Policy

(Updated November 10th 2009)

**As a diversified technology and services company, InfoSpace, Inc. and its subsidiaries (collectively, “InfoSpace”) recognize privacy as an important issue and have prepared this Privacy Policy to inform you of our data collection and use practices and confirm our commitment to keep your personal information secure.**

InfoSpace is a leading developer of metasearch products and services to help people easily search and discover information on the World Wide Web. InfoSpace uses its proprietary metasearch technology that combines the top results from the leading search engines to power a portfolio of branded Web sites and to provide this service and additional content to the Web sites of our distribution partners. We also provide general information about the company, our products and services and communications regarding press releases, employment opportunities other company news through this Web site. 

Please note that this policy only applies to our data collection and use practices for the Web sites owned and operated by InfoSpace identified below (the “InfoSpace Sites”) and our other products and services (collectively, with the InfoSpace Sites, the “InfoSpace Network”) and does not apply to the data collection and use practices of other companies or organizations whose products, services or Web sites you may use or gain access to through the InfoSpace Network. For information on the data collection and use practices of those third parties, please refer to their respective policies and procedures. 

### General Policy

Through the InfoSpace Network and from third party sources, we collect both aggregate data and personal information. A general description of the types of information we collect and how we use that information is provided below. For more specific descriptions of the information we collect and use in connection with a particular InfoSpace Site, please review the privacy policy for that property located below: 

  * [Dogpile](http://www.dogpile.com/dogpile/ws/privacy/rfcid=1234/rfcp=footer-right/_iceUrlFlag=11?_IceUrl=true), [Metacrawler](http://www.metacrawler.com/metacrawler/ws/privacy/_iceUrlFlag=11?_IceUrl=true), [Webcrawler](http://www.webcrawler.com/webcrawler/ws/privacy/_iceUrlFlag=11?_IceUrl=true), and [Nation](http://www.nation.com/about/privacy-policy.aspx)

For a more specific description of the information we collect and use from this Web site, please see the section below entitled “InfoSpace Corporate Web Site.” 

### Types of Information We Collect and Use

In general, we collect and use both anonymous and personal user information and access and use data. We collect this information and data from a variety of sources, including access and use of the InfoSpace Sites or use of our products or services on another Web site in the InfoSpace Network, user submissions, transactions and correspondence, employee and investor relationships and from third parties such as our business partners. 

  * **Anonymous User Information.** When you visit an InfoSpace Site or access or use our products or services on a Web site in the InfoSpace Network, our servers record the information that your browser automatically sends whenever visiting a website, including your web request, the Internet Protocol address and browser configuration of your computer, the date and time of your request, the Uniform Resource Locator (URL) of the referring and exiting Web sites one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser. We generally collect this anonymous (i.e. non–personally identifying) in server log files and use this information for a variety of purposes, including the administration and operation of our Web sites and other properties, identifying and preventing fraud and misuse of our Web sites, products and services, designing and developing new products and services and generally improving the overall quality of your experience.
  * **Personal User Information.** In addition to the anonymous user information above, we may occasionally request from you or you may otherwise voluntarily provide us information that personally identifies you. InfoSpace receives personal user information through its different properties from a broad range of activities, including surveys, contests, registrations, tell–a–friend services and general correspondence. Also, we may receive personal information from third party distribution partners or service providers as part of providing our Web search products and services. Depending on the product or service used, the personal information we collect may include contact information (such as first and last name, mailing address, email address and telephone number), demographic information (such as age, gender, occupation and household income) and billing information (shipping and billing address, credit card information). When we request personal information from you, we will inform you of the type of information we need and the purpose of our use. Except as specifically described in this Privacy Policy and the associated privacy policies of our various properties, we will only use your personal information for the purpose it was collected.

### Cookies

When you visit an InfoSpace Site or use our products or services on another Web site in the InfoSpace Network, one or more cookies, web beacons or action tags may be sent to your computer or otherwise used in connection with your visit or use. A cookie is a small data file that is sent to your computer when you visit a Web site or use a service. When stored on your computer, a cookie uniquely identifies your browser and records your preferences and other data about your visit or use. Cookies are also sometimes used to complete transactions requested by users. Web beacons, also known as web bugs, are small, graphic images that transparently reside on a Web site or other web–based service and are designed to allow the Web site or service owner to monitor who is visiting the Web site or using the service. Action tags assist in delivering cookies and embed a random identifying number on a user’s browser. We use information collected from cookies and web beacons to track which pages our users view, which browsers they use and other information about user activity when visiting an InfoSpace Site or using our products and services. We may also use cookies to help us provide you with personalized features and preferences in a manner that is linked to personal user information you elect to share with us. We use action tags to compile statistics and other data about our users on an aggregate basis. 

We use both session cookies and persistent cookies. For a session cookie, once you close your browser the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie stays stored on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can change the settings on your browser to refuse or notify you prior to accepting cookies and to remove them from your computer. However, some features, products and services may not function properly without cookies. 

On some InfoSpace Sites we engage third party advertisement networks that may place cookies on computers accessing and using those sites that collect non–personal information regarding the content accessed by the computer on those sites. This information may be used by InfoSpace and its third party advertising network partners to identify and target related advertising to the user of such computer, when on Web sites within the third party’s advertising network of sites. Some of these third party advertising networks may be members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) and subject to the NAI Self–Regulatory Principles for Online Preference Marketing by Network Advertisers, available at [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) (the “NAI Principles”). If you would like to opt–out from these services, you may go to the NAI Non–PII Opt–Out Page, located at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp>, or the opt–out page of the particular third party advertising network identified in the cookie. In addition, these companies may offer you a way to directly opt out of ad targeting based on their cookies by visiting their Web sites and following their opt out procedures. 

### InfoSpace Corporate Web site

As a general policy, no personal information is automatically collected from visitors to our corporate Web site, located at [www.infospaceinc.com](http://www.infospaceinc.com/). However, certain anonymous information is recorded by the standard operation of our Web site servers as described above. InfoSpace will only know your email address and any other personal information through our corporate Web site if you voluntarily submit such information to us during a visit to contact us, request information or provide comments. Personally identifiable information you submit to us on this Web site may be stored on individual computers or in a centralized server location, and will be used solely for the purpose received. 

### How We Use Your Personal Information

In general, we only use your personal information for the purpose it was collected, including internally to serve you the Web sites, products and services you request, to enhance and extend our relationship with you, and to improve our products and services. We also use personal information for fulfillment and billing purposes, to complete transactions you have requested, to anticipate and resolve problems with our products and services, to respond to customer support inquiries, to create and inform you of new products and services, and to comply with applicable laws. 

We may access, use, disclose and share any non–personally identifiable information and data we collect for any business purpose and with any third party in our sole discretion. We do not store and retain the Internet Protocol addresses we collect as part of our Web search products and services from the InfoSpace Sites and the Web sites of our distribution partners for longer than six months. 

When you conduct a search on one of our InfoSpace Sites or Web sites within the InfoSpace Network through which we provide our metasearch services, we collect the search terms you submit, along with the information set forth above. We use this information to provide you with relevant search results, including results tailored to your geographic location based on the Internet Protocol address of your computer. This information is also used to maintain and improve the quality, security and integrity of our services and to detect and protect against security threats such as botnet attacks, click fraud and worms. 

More detail about our use of certain types of information we collect is provided above in the section entitled “Types of Information We Collect and Use” and in the privacy policies specific to our different products and services, located as set forth above in the section “General Policy.” 

### Inter–Company Transfers

We may internally transfer the information we collect, including your personal information, to and from the United States and any other country in which we or our agents maintain facilities for the purposes identified above, as well as for storage, processing or other business use as permitted under this Privacy Policy. By accessing or using an InfoSpace Site or other InfoSpace product or service you consent to the transfer of your personal information among these facilities, including those located outside of your country of residence. 

### Sharing Information With Third Parties

In general, we do not sell, rent or otherwise trade your personal information with third parties. However, we may disclose and share your personal information with third parties under the following limited circumstances: 

  * Consent. We have received your consent or permission.
  * Transaction Processing. As necessary to complete a requested transaction, such as verification of your credit card information.
  * Third Party Service Providers. Occasionally, we engage third parties to provide us with products and services, such as support, consulting, statistical analysis and marketing research that may require access to or use of your personal information. In such event, the third party will be obligated to maintain the privacy of any personal information disclosed or shared as part of its provision to us of the product to service and to only use such information for the limited purpose of providing the product or service.
  * Business Transfers. Information about our users and the access and use of the InfoSpace Sites and our products and services is one of our most important business assets. As such, information about our users, including personal information, may be disclosed and transferred as part of any merger or acquisition, creation of a separate business to provide InfoSpace products and services, the sale or pledge of company assets, as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership in which personal information would be transferred as one of the business assets.
  * Protection of InfoSpace; Compliance with Law. We will disclose personal information or remove, destroy or alter personal information in our possession or control when we believe it is necessary to comply with legal process, respond to claims, or to protect the rights, property or safety of our company, its employees, customers or the public.

We may use, disclose and share any anonymous, non–personally identifiable information and data we collect with any third party in our sole discretion. 

### Third Party Information Collection and Use; Links

The InfoSpace Sites and our products and services use and provide access to products, services and content of third parties (collectively, “Third Party Properties”), such as third party search results, directory listings, links and advertisements. Please be aware that we do not control and are not responsible for the information collection and use practices and policies of these third parties, and that by accessing or using Third Party Properties they may collect information regarding your use and access. In general, clicking on links on the InfoSpace Sites or as part of our products and services on our distribution partner’s Web sites, whether part of a search result, advertisement or other content, will allow the third party provider of the result, link or content to collect anonymous, non–personally identifiable information about your browser and activity. We encourage you to be aware when you use a Third Party Property or leave an InfoSpace Site and review any such third party’s data and information collection and use practices and policies with regard to their Web site, products or services. 

### Information Storage and Security

We have implemented and use a variety of industry accepted physical, electronic and managerial policies and procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect to help prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction and to maintain its accuracy and correct use. We generally store the information and data we collect on our own servers in a secure environment and restrict access to your personal information to employees and agents who need to know that information in order to provide you with access and use of the InfoSpace Sites and our products and services, operate and maintain the InfoSpace Sites and our distribution network and as otherwise set forth and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. While we have taken efforts to safeguard and secure your personal information, we cannot guarantee that your information may not be disclosed, altered or destroyed by accidental circumstances or by the unauthorized acts of others. 

### Choice

Typically you will have the choice of whether or not to provide us with personal information. However, you may not be able to access or use some features of the InfoSpace Sites and some of our other products and services if you chose not to provide us with the information required for those products and services. Unless the cost, burden or expense of such access is unwarranted, or the rights of a third party would be violated, we will provide you with the ability to access, correct, update and/or delete the personal information we collect and store from you. Mechanisms for accessing your personal information are either described in the specific privacy policies for the particular InfoSpace Site or other product or service you are using or you may contact us at the contact information provided below. 

### Special Notification with respect to Children’s Privacy (Users under the Age of 13)

In response to concerns about protecting children’s privacy online, Congress enacted the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (“COPPA”), which sets forth rules and procedures governing the ways in which Web sites may collect, use and disclose any personal information for children under the age of 13. In accordance with InfoSpace policy and COPPA regulations, we DO NOT: 

  * Request or knowingly collect personally identifiable information online or offline contact information from users under 13 years of age; or
  * Knowingly use or share personal information from users under 13 years of age with third parties; It is possible that by fraud or deception we may receive information given to us or pertaining to children under 13. If we are notified of this, as soon as we verify the information, we will immediately delete the information from our servers.

Questions regarding children’s privacy should be directed to us at the contact information provided below. 

### Safe Harbor

We abide by the European Union (“EU”) Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding collection, use, and retention of data from the EU. Our privacy practices with respect to personal data collected from individuals residing in the EU are self–certified to the Safe Harbor Program developed by the US Department of Commerce and the European Commission. For more information about the Safe Harbor Program, please go to <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>. Terms that are capitalized below have the same meanings given to them as part of the Safe Harbor Program. 

  * **Compliance with Applicable Law.** We may disclose Personal Data to governmental authorities when required or reasonably requested to do so by such governmental authorities. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the extent that it is in conflict with any law that may be applicable to the Personal Data of a Data Subject.
  * **Safe Harbor Verification.** InfoSpace verifies that this Privacy Policy is accurate, comprehensive, and completely implemented, including implementation of appropriate employee training and other internal procedures. InfoSpace further verifies that its privacy policy conforms to the “Safe Harbor Principles” issued by the U.S. Department of Commerce on July 21, 2000, which concerns compliance with European Union privacy protection requirements by U.S. organizations.

### Enforcement

If you have any questions or concerns regarding our Privacy Policy, please direct them to us at the contact information provided below. We have instituted internal policies and procedures for handling such submissions and will respond to you in a timely manner. If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry, or if it is not satisfactorily addressed, you may contact the Federal Trade Commission for further action on your complaint at <http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/>. 

### Changes to Our Privacy Policy

We will change, amend and update this Privacy Policy and the privacy policies of the various InfoSpace Sites from time to time to reflect changes in our privacy practices, technology, products and services, general business operations and industry. In the event of any such change, we will post a revised policy on this Web site or the Web site of the respective product or service and revise the “Last Updated” date of such policy. We reserve the right to change, amend and update this Privacy Policy, including all of our associated privacy policies, at any time in our sole and absolute discretion, and such changes will be effective upon posting of the revised policy. In the event of a material change in our information collection and use practices, we will provide more prominent notice of such change along with the revision to the effective date of the policy. You should check this Privacy Policy and the policies of the InfoSpace Sites you may access or use on a regular basis to ensure you have reviewed and are familiar with the most current policy. 

### Contacting Us

For any questions or concerns you may have regarding this Privacy Policy and our information and data collection and use practices, please use the information or links below. 

### VIA MAIL:

    InfoSpace, Inc.
    Legal Department, Attn: Privacy Officer
    601 108th Avenue NE, Suite 1200
    Bellevue, Washington 98004 USA

### CONTACT INFORMATION:
